Nikhil Yeole

Software Engineer | 9+ yrs of exp.

nikhil.yeole36@gmail.com | Maharashtra, India.

About me

I know Rust and am trying to get a job in Rust. I have explored server side frameworks (actix, warp, tide, rocket etc) and UI/Webassembly frameworks (yew, seed, iced etc.) in rust. Below are couple of side projects that I built with Rustlang -

1. Actix Web server with Diesel ORM and JWT authentication:

Requirements file: Url to google drive

Git repo: https://bitbucket.org/nikhilyeole1/rust-actix-diesel-jwt-demo/src/master/

2. Webpages scraping tool to scrape public astrology horoscopes:
Git repo: https://bitbucket.org/nikhilyeole1/astro-scraper/src/master/

I am a Javascript/Typescript/Node.js expert with 9+ years of experience. I have also worked as Fullstack Developer and have worked on frontend frameworks like react, angularis, backbone etc.

Also I understand various aspects of languages like Kotlin, Scala, Go, Elm, Purescript, OCaml, Reasonml, Swift, Dart since I have tinkered with them.

I like functional style of programming and I use composition rather than inheritance. I have used functional libraries such as Ramdajs, Lodash-fp, Rxjs etc. I am good at asynchronous/parallel/concurrent programming and understand callbacks, promises, async await, futures, coroutines etc.

I emphasize on understanding requirements clearly and writing concise and modular apis, libraries, interfaces, services etc.

I have worked for startups, product based and service based companies too. Currently I am looking for an individual contributor role.

Some Links:

Blog post on functional javascript:

https://medium.com/front-end-hacking/classless-javascript-composition-over-inheritance-6b27c35893b1

JS SDK for citruspay: https://github.com/citruspay/open-javascript

Github Profile: https://github.com/nikhilyeole1

Technologies

Backend:

Primary Skills-

Rustlang, Javascript, ES, Typescript, Nodejs (with and without Typescript), Microservices, Serverless, Expressjs, SQL and NoSQL databases, Docker, MongoDB, Redis, Rabbitmq, AWS Lambda, AWS (SNS, SQS, S3, APi Gateway, Cloudfront, EC2, LB etc) GCP functions, Google cloud, Firebase, Couchdb, GraphQL etc.

Secondary Skills-

Webassembly, Golang, Kotlin, Scala, Play framework, Spring Webflux, Dartlang, Ruby, PHP, Python

UI/Frontend:

Primary Skills -

All major frontend web frameworks, Hybrid applications with Cordova

Experience	
July 2018 - Mar 2020	Technical Solutions Specialist - IT People, Pune
	Here I worked for a Lenovo Client Project called LanSchool AIR which is a classroom management product.
	Here I worked on backend on Node.js (with Typescript), MongoDB, Microservices, Redis, Websockets, AWS, migration scripts etc
Nov 2016 - April 2018	Full Stack Developer - Mobikon Technologies, Pune
	Mobikon was a startup with cloud product offerings for restaurants.
	Here I worked across the stack (UI and Backend) with technologies such as Typescript, nodejs, microservices, AWS Lambda, SNS, Hybrid apps (with cordova), Scala, Play framework.
Apr 2016 - Aug 2016	Software Engineer - Qualys Security TechServices, Pune
	Qualys has products to scan enterprise networks for security vulnerabilities.
	I worked to migrate UI products from ExtJS stack to react.js/redux. I was coordinating with teammates from Paris and Silicon Valley, USA.
Sep 2015 - Oct 2016	Freelance Software Engineer —
	I worked for couple of project in this period as below -
	1. Citrus javascript payment SDK-
	I wrote javascript payment SDK for them
	https://github.com/citruspay/open-javascript
	2. Client Qualys -
	I helped them in Extjs to Reactjs migration

Sept 2013 - Aug 2015	Senior Software Engineer – Clarice Technologies (now Globant), Pune
	Here I worked on various projects for end clients.
	I worked on both front end and back end projects and used technologies such as Nodejs, Expressjs, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ etc.
June 2010 - June 2011	Software Engineer – BMC Software, Pune, India
	I used to work here on Website development with jQuery, HTML, etc.
Nov 2007 – June 2010	Programmer Analyst— Cognizant, Chennai, India
	I joined cognizant as a fresher and worked on various projects.

Education	
2007	Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics (73%)
	SSGMCE, Shegaon (Amravati University, Maharashtra), India
2003	12th, Science (85%)
2003	J.C. Jr College, Karanja Lad, Washim, Maharashtra, India
Personal Details	
Age	34 yrs
Address	Washim, Maharashtra, India.
LinkedIn Profile	https://in.linkedin.com/pub/nikhil-yeole/10/125/404

Github link

https://github.com/nikhilyeole1/